I don't know what to do I'm always in the dark
Aku tak tahu harus bagaimana Aku selalu tak tahu
Forever's gonna start tonight
Selamanya akan mulai malam ini
Forever's gonna start to--
Selamanya akan mulai...
Once upon a time I was falling in love
Dahulu kala Aku jatuh cinta
Now I'm only falling apart
Kini aku hanya runtuh binasa
There's nothing I can do
Aku tak bisa apa-apa lagi
A total eclipse of the heart
Gerhana penuh dalam hati
Okay. That was a dedication from George to Angela
Baik. Itu penghormatan dari George untuk Angela
after their negative result yesterday.
setelah hasil negatif mereka kemarin.
I'm really sorry, guys. But you know that you are not the only ones.
Aku turut prihatin. Tetapi, kalian tahu kalian bukan yang tepat.
And next, we're going to a dedication from Emma to Craig.
Berikutnya, kami akan menyiarkan penghormatan dari Emma untuk Craig.
And we're gonna hear from the Only Ones the song "Why Don't You Kill Yourself?"
Dan kita akan mendengar lagu dari The Only Ones, "Why Don't You Kill Yourself?"
Okay.
Baik.
I was sorry to hear about St. Leonard's closing down last month.
Aku prihatin St. Leonard ditutup bulan lalu.
- It was such a good school. - Yeah.
- Sekolah itu bagus. - Ya.
Yeah, it was unexpected.
Ya, itu tak terduga.
So you've worked mainly in the third grade.
Jadi terutama kau bekerja untuk kelas tiga.
Yeah. Plus a year in the fifth and a couple in the fourth.
Ya. Ditambah setahun untuk kelas lima dan dua tahun untuk kelas empat.
Can I help?
Aku boleh membantu?
Okay. Could you write "versatile"?
Baik. Apa kau bisa menulis "serbabisa"?
Versatile.
Serbabisa.
How'd it go?
Bagaimana hasilnya?
Sorry. That's really personal.
Maaf. Itu sangat bersifat pribadi.
No. It's okay.
Tidak. Tak apa.
It didn't go so well actually, but it's fine.
Sebenarnya tak berjalan lancar, tetapi tak apa.
I'm used to it by now.
Kini aku terbiasa.
What about you? Have you tested?
Kau bagaimana? Kau sudah dites?
Yeah. My boyfriend and I are positive.
Ya. Pacarku dan aku positif.
You're one of the lucky ones.
Kau termasuk yang mujur.
"And she looked at the tree and said, 'Wow.
"Dan gadis melihat pohon dan berkata, 'Wah.
Those apples look so tasty.'
Apel itu tampak sangat lezat.'
And he looked at her, and he said, 'Yeah, they do.
Dan pemuda itu menatapnya, dan berkata, 'Ya, benar.
We should eat one together.'
Kita harus makan satu bersama.'
So they picked the apple off the tree,
Jadi mereka memetik apel dari pohon,
split it and shared it while gazing into each other's eyes."
membelahnya, dan membaginya sambil saling menatap satu sama lain."
And then this is word for word,
Lalu ini ditulis secara harfiah,
"It was peaceful in paradise,
"Suasananya damai di surga,
for there were no animals around to disturb them
karena tak ada hewan di sekitar untuk mengganggu mereka
or their love for each other."
atau cinta mereka untuk satu sama lain."
That's what the poster says?
Itu tulisan di poster?
Yeah. It was at the principal's office.
Ya. Itu ada di kantor kepala sekolah.
Can you imagine what they're teaching these kids?
Kau bisa bayangkan ajaran mereka kepada anak-anak?
I think that's gone too far.
Kurasa itu keterlaluan.
I don't think they should change a story that old.
Kurasa mereka tak boleh mengubah kisah setua itu.
Why? Did it even really happen?
Kenapa? Apa itu memang terjadi?
I'll get it.
Akan kuangkat.
Hello?
Halo?
Yes, this is she.
Ya, ini orangnya.
Yes.
Ya.
I came by and left my CV a few times.
Aku mampir dan meninggalkan CV-ku beberapa kali.
At the Love Institute?
Di Institut Cinta?
Great.
Bagus.
At noon? Great.
Tengah hari? Bagus.
Okay. Have a nice evening.
Baik. Selamat malam.
- Another interview? - Yeah.
- Wawancara lain? - Ya.
That's great. Where is it?
Itu bagus. Di mana?
Pinewood Elementary School.
Sekolah Dasar Pinewood.
Is that good?
Apa sebagus itu?
- Yeah. - Yeah?
- Ya. - Ya?
Yeah. Yeah, they have, like-- a lot of famous people studied there.
Ya, ada banyak orang terkenal yang bersekolah di sana.
Really? Like who?
Sungguh? Misalnya siapa?
Ginger Spice.
Ginger Spice.
- Wow. - Yeah.
- Wah. - Ya.
She's my favorite.
Dia favoritku.
I know.
Aku tahu.
Andy here is a great cook.
Andy koki yang hebat.
Thank you. Yeah, it's a Spanish recipe.
Terima kasih. Ya, ini resep Spanyol.
We've been trying to save up for a vacation,
Kami mencoba menghemat untuk liburan,
and we were thinking of going to Spain.
dan kami berpikir untuk pergi ke Spanyol.
Carrie's been there once. It was before she met me.
Carrie pernah ke sana. Sebelum bertemu denganku.
Yeah, I went to Madrid with one of my exes,
Ya, aku pergi ke Madrid dengan, salah satu mantanku,
a thousand years ago.
seribu tahun yang lalu.
How did you guys meet?
Bagaimana kalian berkenalan?
It was at a friend's wedding.
Itu di pernikahan teman.
We were both sitting at the singles table.
Kami berdua duduk di meja lajang.
It was us, an 80-year-old fireman and a nerdy biology student.
Itu aku, pemadam kebakaran usia 80 tahun dan mahasiswa biologi kuper.
So, tough choice.
Jadi, pilihannya sulit.
And how long have you been together?
Dan berapa lama kalian berpacaran?
- It's been 94 days. - Three months.
- Tiga bulan. - Sudah 94 hari.
Nice.
Bagus.
And have you thought about taking the test?
Dan kalian sudah memikirkan untuk melakukan tes?
I mean, you know my opinion.
Maksudku, kau tahu opiniku.
We don't believe in it.
Kami tak percaya soal itu.
The whole crisis overreaction thing, it's pretty stupid.
Seluruh situasi reaksi berlebihan tentang krisis, itu cukup bodoh.
- Really good. - Yeah, great.
- Sungguh bagus. - Ya, hebat.
We could take some dance classes.
Kita bisa ikut les tari.
Yeah.
Ya.
I gotta use the restroom.
Aku harus ke toilet.
Can I ask you something?
Boleh aku bertanya?
Have you guys taken the test?
Apa kalian melakukan tesnya?
- Yeah.
- Ya.
Yeah, it was about three years ago.
Ya, itu sekitar tiga tahun yang lalu.
We were positive.
Kami positif.
- Nice. - Yeah.
- Bagus. - Ya.
And how did it feel? I mean, when you got your results.
Dan bagaimana rasanya? Maksudku, saat kalian dapat hasilnya.
Yeah, I think more than anything it felt kind of like a relief.
Ya, kurasa lebih dari apa pun rasanya seperti melegakan.
You know, it was like a weight had been lifted.
Begitulah, ibarat beban terlepas.
You know, Garth doesn't believe in taking the test.
Garth tak percaya tentang melakukan tes.
He says he doesn't need a certificate to tell him if we're in love.
Katanya dia tak perlu sertifikat untuk mengatakan apa kami jatuh cinta.
And he also thinks losing a nail is ridiculous.
Dan dia juga berpikir kehilangan kuku itu konyol.
And you? What do you think?
Dan kau? Bagaimana menurutmu?
You know, more and more of my friends have taken it,
Makin banyak temanku yang melakukannya,
and I thought maybe we could too, but--
dan kupikir mungkin kami juga bisa, tetapi...
You know, Anna wanted us to go and, go to the institute
Anna ingin kami pergi dan, pergi ke institut
just do the exercises, you know, last summer,
untuk melakukan latihan, musim panas lalu,
but I thought it was completely unnecessary.
tetapi kupikir itu sungguh tak perlu.
You know, we had tested positive without the extra help, and--
Kami dites positif tanpa bantuan tambahan, dan...
and even if sometimes our relationship settles into routine,
dan bahkan jika kadang hubungan kami menjadi rutin,
we don't need to question that.
kami tak perlu mempertanyakan itu.
- All right. This is for you. - Great.
- Baik. Ini untukmu. - Bagus.
Just fill this out, and Duncan will be with you shortly.
Isi saja ini, dan Duncan akan segera bersamamu.
Thank you. Excuse me. Can I ask, is it raining?
Terima kasih. Maaf. Aku boleh bertanya, apa hujan?
No. No, they just pump that through the entire building.
Tidak, bunyi itu cuma dipasang di seluruh gedung.
Rain makes people feel romantic.
Hujan membuat orang merasa romantis.
Yeah, it does.
Ya, benar.
I keep asking them to turn it down.
Aku terus minta volumenya diredakan.
It just makes me need to pee.
Hanya membuatku ingin pipis.
I often put his happiness before my own.
Aku sering lebih mengutamakan kebahagiaannya.
When we have rib eye for dinner,
Saat kami makan malam rib eye,
I know that he likes the fatty bits of the steak.
aku tahu dia suka bagian steik yang berlemak.
So that-- Well, I cut them off mine and give them to him
Jadi... Kupotong bagian milikku dan kuberikan kepadanya
and pretend that I don't like them, but actually I love them.
dan pura-pura aku tak suka, tetapi sebenarnya aku suka.
They're my favorite part.
Itu bagian favoritku.
And may I ask you something personal?
Boleh kutanyakan hal pribadi?
Do you still have strong feelings for him?
Apa kau masih sangat mencintainya?
Yes. Yeah.
Ya.
Yeah, I love him.
Ya, aku mencintainya.
You do have your love certificate, so that's not a problem, but--
Kau punya sertifikat cintamu, jadi itu bukan masalah, tetapi...
Well, most of our recent applicants have all been in an institute as clients.
Sebagian besar pelamar baru-baru ini sudah menjadi klien di institut kita.
So they know what it's like to do these exercises as a couple.
Jadi mereka tahu apa rasanya melakukan latihan sebagai pasangan.
Yeah. Well, they weren't around yet, but--
Ya. Mereka belum datang, tetapi,
I really wanna learn how the exercises help you connect more, you know?
aku ingin belajar cara latihan membantu untuk lebih terhubung, ya?
And you guys, you're the best.
Dan kalian yang terbaik.
Well, it's not easy, but we try.
Tak mudah, tetapi kami mencoba.
Now, Anna, as a teacher, I have to ask you,
Anna, sebagai guru, aku harus bertanya,
you wouldn't prefer to work in a school?
apa kau tak lebih suka bekerja di sekolah?
No. I really want to work here.
Tidak. Aku sungguh mau bekerja di sini.
- Hey! - Hey.
- Hei! - Hei.
Made you dinner to celebrate the new job.
Kubuatkan makan malam untuk merayakan pekerjaan baru.
How do you know that?
Bagaimana kau tahu itu?
They called a couple hours ago.
Mereka menelepon dua jam lalu.
I said you were out, so they left a message,
Kataku kau pergi, mereka tinggalkan pesan,
and the school secretary wants to talk to you tomorrow about the details.
dan, sekretaris sekolah ingin bicara besok tentang perinciannya.
Fuck. I didn't realize you were talking about
Sial. Aku tak menyadari kau membicarakan
the interview the day before yesterday,
wawancara kemarin lusa,
'cause today I went to Pinewood Elementary School,
karena hari ini aku pergi ke Sekolah Dasar Pinewood,
and they hired me on the spot.
dan aku langsung diterima.
That's great. Did you take it?
Itu hebat. Kau menerimanya?
- Yeah. - Yeah?
- Ya. - Ya?
- Great.
- Bagus.
- Congratulations. Come on. - Thank you.
- Selamat. Ayo. - Terima kasih.
Excuse me. This would not make Amir happy.
Permisi. Ini tak akan membuat Amir senang.
I was just about to say
Aku baru akan mengatakan
that the reason they come to us is to take the risk out of love.
alasan mereka mendatangi kita adalah melenyapkan risiko cinta.
No more uncertainty.
Tak ada ketidakpastian lagi.
No more wondering if you've chosen the right partner.
Tak ada rasa penasaran lagi apa kau memilih pasangan tepat.
No more divorce.
Tak ada perceraian lagi.
Now, you know that five years ago,
Kalian tahu lima tahun yang lalu,
the test was developed in order to define love relationships
tes dikembangkan untuk menentukan hubungan cinta
because there was concern people weren't falling in love.
karena ada kekhawatiran orang tak jatuh cinta.
However, what they couldn't have anticipated was
Namun, yang tak bisa mereka antisipasi
the fact that 87% of the couples that took the test
yaitu 87% pasangan yang melakukan tes
received a negative result.
menerima hasil negatif.
It was a staggering statistic.
Itu statistik yang mengejutkan.
Couples broke apart.
Pasangan putus.
And people suffered a great deal.
Dan orang sangat menderita.
And you're all aware of the crisis that followed,
Dan kalian tahu krisis setelah itu,
the insecurity that this created in most couples.
ketidakpastian yang diciptakan hal ini dalam sebagian besar pasangan.
And that's why I founded this institute.
Itu sebabnya kudirikan institut ini.
We were the first to buy the machines to conduct the test,
Kami yang pertama membeli mesin untuk menjalankan tes,
and I created the program to make the bond of love stronger.
dan kubuat program agar ikatan cinta lebih kuat.
We're not here to try to teach people to fall in love.
Kita di sini bukan untuk mengajari orang jatuh cinta.
That would be insane.
Itu akan gila.
We're here to try to bring them closer together.
Kita di sini untuk mencoba agar mereka lebih akrab.
Now, yes, the success rate, it's still low.
Kini, ya, tingkat keberhasilannya masih rendah.
But thanks to this institute and others who imitate us,
Tetapi berkat institut ini dan yang lain yang meniru kita,
the numbers are slowly increasing.
jumlahnya perlahan meningkat.
At this point, the test, it's more popular than ever.
Pada saat ini, tesnya paling populer.
So that shows that people are searching for an answer,
Jadi itu menunjukkan orang mencari jawaban,
even if it's not the one they want to hear.
bahkan jika bukan yang ingin mereka dengar.
Now, I hope that, as new employees, you'll--
Kini, aku berharap, sebagai karyawan baru, kalian akan...
- Sorry, I'm late. - You'll--
- Maaf, aku terlambat. - Kau akan...
- That's okay. Hi. - Hey.
- Itu tak apa. Hai. - Hei.
I--
Aku...
Anyhow, what I was gonna say was,
Begitulah, maksudku,
in the past, I think we prioritized seemingly more important things over love
pada masa lalu, kurasa kita mengutamakan hal yang tampak lebih penting dari cinta
when the truth is...
padahal sebenarnya,
we're all achingly lonely.
kita semua merasa sangat kesepian.
And we're endlessly searching for ways to fill that void.
Dan kita terus mencari cara untuk mengisi kehampaan itu.
Anyhow, each month, we change the courses
Begitulah, tiap bulan, kita mengubah jalur
so the couples, they don't know the structure of the program.
agar para pasangan tak tahu struktur program.
And Amir, one of our instructors,
Dan Amir, salah satu instruktur,
he's been kind enough to design and build these maquettes
dia baik hati untuk merancang dan membangun maket ini
to help illustrate what's included in those materials,
untuk membantu menggambarkan hal yang termasuk dalam program itu,
if you'd like to come take a look.
jika kalian mau melihatnya.
The first one, it's-- well, it's kind of a domestic scene.
Yang pertama, itu agak seperti adegan rumah tangga.
You'll see that when one leaves,
Kalian akan lihat ketika yang satu pergi,
the other one may give themselves a small electroshock
yang satu lagi mungkin beri kejut listrik kecil kepada diri sendiri
with the equipment we will have provided them with.
dengan peralatan yang akan kita sediakan untuknya.
The person must associate the two pains.
Orang itu harus mengaitkan dua rasa sakit.
The loss of one manifests itself in--
Kehilangan seseorang muncul sendiri,
in actual physical pain for the one left behind.
dalam rasa sakit asli untuk orang yang ditinggalkan.
Do you understand?
Apa kalian paham?
The second, it's kind of a sporting scene designed by Amir.
Yang kedua, adegan olahraga yang dirancang Amir.
Couples engage in a series of pair-based competitive activities
Pasangan melakukan serangkaian kegiatan kompetitif yang berpasangan
in the hopes that they'll be bonded together.
dengan harapan mereka akan lebih akrab.
And this is one we've just talked about
Dan yang ini baru kita bicarakan
but haven't yet had the chance to implement.
tetapi belum sempat diterapkan.
We want to create a fake fire in a movie theater,
Kami ingin membuat kebakaran palsu di bioskop,
where the clients are gathered.
ketika para klien berkumpul.
Now, they'd be unaware that it's a simulation.
Mereka tak akan tahu itu simulasi.
Right now, what we do is we have them watch romantic movies,
Saat ini, tindakan kami adalah membuat mereka menonton film romantis,
but with the fire, we'd really be able to--
tetapi dengan kebakaran, kita akan bisa
to gauge their reaction and see just how protective they are of their other half.
menilai reaksi mereka, melihat sebesar apa perlindungan mereka atas pasangannya.
We've also recently acquired the rights to a compilation--
Kami juga baru-baru ini mendapat hak untuk kompilasi...
Alexandra?
Alexandra?
Compilation of classic love songs in their French version
Kompilasi lagu cinta klasik dalam versi Prancis-nya
to be used in our musical exercises.
untuk digunakan dalam latihan musik kita.
If you'd queue that up, please.
Tolong pasang itu.
Do you have any other questions?
Kau punya pertanyaan lain?
How often do people get 50%?
Sesering apa orang mendapat 50%?
Not a lot. Not a lot, but sometimes.
Tak banyak, tetapi sesekali.
And those are often the hardest cases
Dan seringnya itu kasus tersulit
when only one person is in love.
ketika hanya satu orang yang jatuh cinta.
Especially when the machine,
Khususnya ketika mesin,
it can't identify which member of the couple is in love.
tak bisa mengenali anggota mana dari pasangan itu yang jatuh cinta.
Do they ever come back to retest?
Apa mereka pernah kembali untuk ulangi tes?
Sometimes.
Sesekali.
But it really depends on them, whether or when they will retest or not.
Tetapi tergantung pada mereka, mau diulang atau tidak, dan kapan.
And one more question I've been wondering.
Dan satu pertanyaan lagi.
What do we do if someone doesn't have arms?
Apa yang kita lakukan jika seseorang tak punya lengan?
To be honest...
Jujur saja...
well, I have no idea.
aku tak tahu.
Yeah.
Ya.
Hey.
Hei.
Sorry.
Maaf.
- Hey. - So, you'll be shadowing Amir.
- Hei. - Jadi, kau mendampingi Amir.
He's only been here for a few months,
Dia hanya di sini beberapa bulan,
but he's already one of our most successful instructors.
tetapi dia sudah menjadi salah satu instruktur paling sukses.
Great.
Bagus.
Here. We give this to all of our clients.
Di sini. Kita memberi ini untuk semua klien.
This one explains the exercise where they need to draw one another.
Yang ini menjelaskan latihan ketika mereka harus saling melukis satu sama lain.
Interesting. Can I ask you something?
Menarik. Aku boleh bertanya?
Why are the songs in French?
Kenapa lagunya berbahasa Prancis?
Il Français est la linguage plus érotique, non?
Il français est la linguage plus érotique, non?
Oui.
Oui.
Hi.
Hai.
- I'm Amir. - Hi.
- Aku Amir. - Hai.
I'm Anna.
Aku Anna.
I'll be shadowing you this session.
Aku akan mendampingimu sesi ini.
Cool.
Bagus.
Just so you know, you're my first trainee,
Asal tahu saja, kau pegawai magang pertamaku,
so I'll do my best.
jadi aku akan melakukan sebaiknya.
Great. Well, we're gonna be spending our first week doing intake interviews.
Bagus. Kita akan menghabiskan pekan pertama melakukan wawancara awal.
You know, new couples. So, I'll get the files.
Begitulah, pasangan baru. Jadi, aku akan ambil berkasnya.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Is that your partner?
Apa itu pasanganmu?
Natasha.
Natasha.
- You guys look great together. - Thank you.
- Kalian tampak hebat bersama. - Terima kasih.
It's our two-year anniversary in a couple of weeks.
Dua pekan lagi hari jadi kami tahun kedua.
How did you meet?
Bagaimana kalian bertemu?
We met at a video store.
Kami bertemu di toko video.
We both wanted to rent Breakfast at Tiffany's.
Kami ingin menyewa Breakfast at Tiffany's.
There was only one copy left, so we watched it together.
Hanya ada satu salinan, jadi kami menontonnya bersama.
That's amazing.
Itu mengagumkan.
No, I'm joking. No, we just met normally.
Tidak, aku bercanda. Tidak, kami hanya bertemu secara normal.
So you've been together for six months?
Jadi, kalian berpacaran selama enam bulan?
- Yes.
- Ya.
And you both work together at the accounting office?
Dan kalian bekerja bersama di kantor akuntansi?
- Yes.
- Ya.
It's nice to have similar interests.
Bagus untuk memiliki minat serupa?
Accounting.
Akuntansi.
Okay. John, I'm gonna ask you first.
Baik. John, aku akan bertanya dahulu.
What's the one thing you love most about Maria
Apa satu hal yang paling kausukai tentang Maria
that makes you certain she is the ideal partner for you?
yang membuatmu yakin dia pasangan ideal untukmu?
That's the first question?
Itu pertanyaan pertama?
I'm supposed to answer that now?
Aku harus menjawabnya sekarang?
Take your time. And reply from the heart.
Tak perlu buru-buru. Dan jawab dengan tulus.
Sorry, is-- What is-- Is that--
Maaf... Apa... Itu...
Isn't it a little bit early for that question?
Bukankah agak awal untuk pertanyaan itu?
- No, that's a-- - Well, it's just 'cause--
- Tidak, itu... - Itu karena...
I love her hair. It's soft.
Aku suka rambutnya. Lembut.
And her...
Dan...
voice.
suaranya.
Yes, her voice even more.
Ya, lebih suka suaranya.
It soothes me.
Itu membuatku tenang.
- That's a nice answer. - It's nice.
- Jawaban itu bagus. - Bagus.
Rob is also a great dancer...
Rob juga penari yang andal,
but he never dances with me at parties.
tetapi dia tak pernah menari denganku di pesta.
He feels embarrassed in front of other people.
Dia merasa malu di depan orang lain.
But it's fun, 'cause at home he puts on music and dances alone for hours.
Tetapi asyik, sebab di rumah dia pasang musik dan menari sendirian berjam-jam.
And you, Rob?
Dan kau, Rob?
I think I'm a good dancer.
Kurasa aku penari yang bagus.
No, h--
Tidak...
How does Sally make you feel?
Bagaimana perasaanmu tentang Sally?
Well, when we're together,
Begini, saat kami berpacaran,
I feel as if I'm... invisible.
aku merasa ibarat aku tak terlihat.
So what do you mean by that?
Jadi, apa maksudmu soal itu?
I feel like, normally, people are always looking at me,
Aku merasa, normalnya, orang selalu menatapku,
and I'm always aware of that feeling.
dan aku selalu merasakan itu.
Outside. Apart. But I--
Di luar. Terpisah. Tetapi aku,
I don't have that when I'm with her.
aku tak merasa begitu bila bersamanya.
I just blend into her.
Aku hanya melebur dengannya.
Okay.
Baik.
I think that's good for today.
Kurasa cukup untuk hari ini.
Do you think they're lonely together?
Kau pikir mereka kesepian bersama?
I don't know. Or-- Maybe.
Entahlah. Atau... Mungkin.
I know you can't really tell from one image,
Tentu kau tak bisa tahu dari satu pandangan,
but I don't know, there's just something really--
tetapi entahlah, ada yang sangat...
Should we order drinks while we wait?
Apa kita pesan minuman selagi menunggu?
Oui. D'accord, mon amour.
Oui. D'accord, mon amour.
What?
Apa?
Nothing.
Tak ada.
"Spaghetti carbonara." Yum.
"Spageti carbonara." Lezat.
Actually, I wanna have the "rib eye with caramelized onions."
Sebenarnya, aku mau "rib eye dengan bawang dikaramelisasi."
Yes.
Ya.
Are you sure? You always only eat half. Why don't you go ahead and get the--
Kau yakin? Kau selalu hanya makan separuh. Kenapa kau pesan saja...
- Sorry for being late. - Hey.
- Maaf terlambat. - Hei.
Hi.
Hai.
What's that?
Apa itu?
Andy-- We took the test again.
Andy... Kami melakukan tes lagi.
I need a drink.
Aku perlu minum.
Hey.
Hei.
Could I have just a glass of red wine?
Apa aku boleh minta segelas anggur merah?
- Just make it three glasses, please. - We'll make it a bottle.
- Buatlah itu, tiga gelas. - Kami pesan sebotol.
It was positive.
Itu positif.
Fuck you.
Kau berengsek.
That's not funny.
Itu tak lucu.
- That's great. Great. - Yeah.
- Itu hebat. - Ya.
Yeah, yeah. Congratulations.
Ya. Selamat.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Why did you guys take the test again though?
Kenapa kalian melakukan tes lagi?
We've been having some arguments,
Kami sering bertengkar,
and Andy thought it would be a good idea to know again.
dan Andy berpikir akan jadi ide bagus untuk tahu lagi.
Even if I told him there would be a lot of risk.
Bahkan jika kataku akan ada banyak risiko.
But I hope there's no need to do it again.
Tetap semoga tak perlu melakukannya lagi.
I really don't get it.
Aku sungguh tak paham.
So many couples would kill to have a positive result.
Banyak pasangan ingin sekali mendapat hasil positif.
Why would they risk it?
Kenapa mau membahayakannya?
What's that?
Apa itu?
Probably nothing.
Mungkin tak penting.
No. No, we should get it booked for a service.
Tidak, kita harus menjadwalkan untuk servis.
With you I'm in real danger.
Denganmu aku terkena bahaya.
It seems like a perfect situation, apart from that foul temper of yours,
Tampaknya seperti situasi sempurna, kecuali sikapmu yang buruk,
but my relatively inexperienced heart would, I fear, not recover,
tetapi hatiku yang relatif belum berpengalaman takutnya, tak pulih,
if I was, once again, cast aside as I would absolutely expect to be.
jika aku, sekali lagi, disingkirkan sebagaimana yang kuperkirakan.
There are just too many pictures of you, too many...
Ada terlalu banyak fotomu, terlalu banyak...
You know, you'd go and I'd be--
Begitulah, kau pergi dan aku jadi,
- well, buggered, basically. - Wait.
- begitulah, kesal, pada dasarnya. - Tunggu.
That really is a real no, isn't it?
Itu tidak boleh sama sekali, bukan?
I live in Notting Hill. You live in Beverly Hills.
Aku tinggal di Notting Hill. Kau tinggal di Beverly Hills.
Everyone in the world knows who you are. My mother has trouble remembering my name.
Semua orang di dunia tahu siapa kau. Ibuku sulit mengingat namaku.
Fine.
Baiklah.
The fire was such a good idea.
Kebakaran itu ide bagus.
Yeah, the cinema owner got cold feet.
Ya, pemilik bioskop tak berani.
It wasn't even that dangerous. I mean, what's the worst that can happen?
Itu bahkan tak terlalu berbahaya. Apa hal terburuk yang bisa terjadi?
We've always had movies in the program.
Dalam program kita selalu ada film.
Duncan thinks it's crucial. I just don't see it.
Duncan berpikir itu penting. Aku cuma tak setuju.
Everything's too simple in films.
Semua terlalu mudah di film-film.
Besides, watching a love story feels safe.
Lagi pula, menonton film cinta terasa aman.
Being in love doesn't.
Jatuh cinta tak begitu.
No, I prefer doing exercises based on the movies, you know?
Tidak, aku lebih suka melakukan latihan berdasarkan film, ya?
Like Titanic?
Seperti Titanic?
Do you like romantic movies?
Kau suka film romantis?
Nah, I like horrors.
Tidak, aku suka horor.
That's all right. Yeah. Don't worry if you're tired.
Itu tak apa. Ya. Jangan cemas jika kau lelah.
Can watch a movie at home. Okay.
Bisa menonton film di rumah. Baik.
I'll see you later. Bye. Love you, bye.
Sampai nanti. Aku mencintaimu, sampai jumpa.
- Sorry.
- Maaf.
Are you leaving?
Kau akan pergi?
I'm just going. Sorry.
Aku keluar saja. Maaf.
- Oh, Anna? - Yeah?
- Anna? - Ya?
Y-- Really great job this week.
Hasil kerjamu bagus pekan ini.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
- Okay. - Bye.
- Baik. - Sampai jumpa.
Bye.
Sampai jumpa.
Each year, caribou undertake a long and perilous journey,
Tiap tahun, karibu melakukan perjalanan panjang dan berbahaya,
migrating from their wintering grounds to their summering grounds.
bermigrasi dari dataran musim dingin ke dataran musim panas mereka.
The journey begins in winter
Perjalanan dimulai pada musim dingin
when the caribou leave their wintering grounds in the boreal forest.
ketika karibu meninggalkan dataran musim dingin ke hutan boreal.
They travel south,
Mereka pergi ke selatan,
following the snowmelt, until they reach their summering grounds in the tundra.
mengikuti lelehan salju, hingga mencapai dataran musim panas di tundra.
These things always make me cry.
Hal-hal ini selalu membuatku menangis.
...a thousand miles long.
...sepanjang 1609 kilometer.
And it takes the caribou several months to complete.
Dan karibu perlu beberapa bulan untuk menyelesaikannya.
Can I--
Apa aku boleh...
I'm running an art project at school where everyone draws a member of their family.
Aku menjalankan proyek seni di sekolah ketika semua menggambar anggota keluarga.
That's nice.
Itu bagus.
Can I draw you?
Aku boleh menggambarmu?
- Really? - Yeah.
- Sungguh? - Ya.
It'll be fun.
Akan menyenangkan.
You mean, like, now?
Maksudmu, sekarang?
Yeah. You don't have to do anything.
Ya. Kau tak harus melakukan apa-apa.
I can keep watching the documentary?
Aku boleh terus menonton dokumenter?
I really wanna see what happens to the caribou.
Aku sungguh ingin melihat yang terjadi pada karibu.
That's fine. I'm gonna get my things.
Tak apa. Aku akan ambil perlengkapanku.
And their hooves are sharp and pointed.
Dan kuku mereka tajam dan runcing.
It is a reminder that even in the harshest of environments, life can thrive.
Itu pengingat bahwa bahkan di lingkungan yang paling keras, kehidupan bisa sukses.
The caribou's journey is also important for the arctic ecosystem.
Perjalanan karibu juga penting untuk ekosistem arktika.
- Do you wanna draw me after? - The caribou are a keystone species.
- Kau mau menggambarku setelah ini? - Karibu adalah spesies penting.
- Tonight? - Yeah.
- Malam ini? - Ya.
Why?
Kenapa?
...source for many other animals.
...sumber bagi banyak hewan lain.
I don't know. It'd be nice.
Entahlah. Akan menyenangkan.
That's part of the project or...
Itu termasuk proyek atau...
No. Don't worry.
Tidak. Jangan cemas.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- Ini untukmu. - Terima kasih.
Did you want milk and sugar?
Kau mau susu dan gula?
No, it's okay.
Tidak usah.
It has both.
Ada keduanya.
Excuse me. Sorry to bother.
Maaf. Maaf mengganggu.
I just had a question. Is this task based on a movie?
Aku cuma ada pertanyaan. Apa tugas ini berdasarkan film?
It reminds me of something.
Ini mengingatkanku akan sesuatu.
It is.
Memang.
It's based on the opening scene of a movie named Jaws.
Berdasarkan adegan pembuka film bernama Jaws.
Heard of it?
Pernah dengar?
I'm joking. It's-- I don't think it's based on a movie.
Aku bercanda. Kurasa bukan berdasarkan film.
Okay. Thank you.
Baik. Terima kasih.
They seem so good together.
Tampaknya mereka cocok bersama.
I don't know. I-- Maybe--
Entahlah. Aku... Mungkin...
I think they've got something real.
Kurasa hubungan mereka tulus.
Don't get too carried away.
Jangan terlalu terbawa perasaan.
You know, it's difficult to make your first big love last. People change.
Sulit untuk melanggengkan cinta pertama yang kuat. Orang berubah.
I know. They're only 21.
Aku tahu. Usia mereka baru 21 tahun.
You never know.
Kita tak pernah tahu.
I mean, it's possible for people to change together.
Maksudku, mungkin saja orang berubah bersama.
- I think it's time to start. - Okay.
- Kurasa sudah saatnya mulai. - Baik.
Okay. As I told you, main thing to watch out for is, are their eyes open?
Baik. Seperti kataku, yang terutama harus diawasi, apa mata mereka terbuka?
And then how much are they moving around? How much are they still?
Sebanyak apa mereka bergerak? Selama apa mereka diam saja?
Basically, have they drowned?
Apa mereka tenggelam?
Ideally, we don't want anyone dying on us. Again.
Idealnya, jangan sampai ada yang tewas. Lagi.
Yeah.
Ya.
Remember, the aim is to hold eye contact underwater for one minute.
Ingat, tujuannya tetap saling menatap di bawah air selama satu menit.
Okay? Three, two, one. Let's go.
Ya? Tiga, dua, satu. Ayo mulai.
- Hi. - Hey.
- Hai. - Hei.
- You okay? - Yeah.
- Kau tak apa? - Ya.
This is just stuck.
Ini macet.
Let me help you.
Biar kubantu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
All right. One, two...
Baik. Satu, dua...
Oh, my God, it really is stuck.
Astaga, memang macet.
God, it really--
Astaga, sungguh...
Sorry.
Maaf.
I actually think it looks cooler like that.
Menurutku lebih keren seperti itu.
- Yeah. - I might leave it.
- Ya. - Mungkin kubiarkan saja.
Yeah. It looks great.
Ya. Itu tampak hebat.
Yeah, I'll just take it to the garage tomorrow. Thank you.
Ya, aku akan bawa ke bengkel besok. Terima kasih.
Okay.
Baiklah.
- Okay, bye. See you tomorrow. - See ya.
- Sampai jumpa. Sampai besok. - Sampai jumpa.
Bye.
Sampai jumpa.
Ryan?
Ryan?
Okay, Rob.
Baik, Rob.
Sally, step back.
Sally, mundur.
And let's go.
Dan ayo mulai.
Okay.
Baik.
Two, three. Okay.
Dua, tiga. Baik.
Go.
Mulai.
- Oh, God. - Easy. Easy there.
- Astaga. - Pelan-pelan di sana.
Gently, please. Sorry about that.
Pelan-pelan. Maaf soal itu.
Rob, that's a wall. Yeah, everybody's kind of back this way.
Rob, itu tembok. Ya, semuanya ada di belakang sini.
No t-- No touching, Rob. No touching. Thank you.
Tidak... Jangan sentuh, Rob. Jangan sentuh. Terima kasih.
I think I found her.
Kurasa aku menemukannya.
Let's find out. Take off that blindfold.
Ayo cari tahu. Lepaskan penutup mata itu.
Oh, yes. Yes, yes.
Ya. Ya.
Wunderbar.
Wunderbar.
What was that?
Apa itu?
It means "wonderful." It's--
Artinya "hebat". Itu...
What? Okay, I haven't heard that before.
Apa? Baik, aku belum pernah dengar itu.
Okay. Thank you, everyone. Well done, and let's take a break.
Baik. Terima kasih, semuanya. Bagus, dan ayo beristirahat.
- Can I try something? I've got an idea. - Yeah, yeah. Sure.
- Boleh kucoba sesuatu? Aku punya ide. - Ya. Tentu.
That was really great.
Itu hebat sekali.
I know we asked you not to shower for a few days
Aku tahu kami minta kalian tak mandi selama beberapa hari
in preparation for this exercise,
untuk persiapan latihan ini,
but I was wondering maybe if you wanted to try and take a shower together?
tetapi aku ingin tahu apa kalian mau mandi bersama?
It can be very intimate to wash each other's bodies.
Akan bisa jadi sangat intim untuk saling membilas tubuh satu sama lain.
It might help deepen your connection.
Mungkin bisa membantu memperdalam hubungan kalian.
Okay.
Baik.
- Yeah? - Yeah, we'll do it.
- Ya? - Ya, kami akan lakukan.
- Okay. Good work. - Great. Great.
- Baik. Bagus. - Hebat. Hebat.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
That is a really good idea.
Ide itu sangat bagus.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- Ya? - Ya.
Yeah. Really, really... It's great.
Ya. Sungguh... Hebat.
Seriously.
Serius.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Yeah, well, it's-- I don't-- It's--
Ya, begitulah... aku tak...
Ryan and I bathe together all the time.
Ryan dan aku selalu berendam bersama.
- Yeah. - Right.
- Ya. - Benar.
Don't-- you and Natasha?
Bagaimana kau dan Natasha?
I think it could help them deepen their connection.
Kurasa itu bisa membantu mereka memperdalam hubungan mereka.
- Yeah. Yeah. Sure. Yeah. - You know? That's what you said.
- Ya. Tentu. Ya. - Paham? Itu ucapanmu.
Fuck.
Sial.
- You want a coffee before you go? - No, thank you.
- Mau kopi sebelum pergi? - Tidak usah.
Hey, how are you gonna get in today?
Hei, bagaimana kau pergi bekerja hari ini?
- Taking the bus is really easy. - Yeah?
- Naik bus sangat mudah. - Ya?
Straight to the school gates.
Langsung ke gerbang sekolah.
That's great.
Itu bagus.
Hey, have you met any kids you think could become famous yet?
Hei, apa kau, sudah bertemu anak yang menurutmu bisa jadi terkenal?
Yeah.
Ya.
There's a boy who's very good at Ping-Pong.
Ada anak lelaki yang sangat pandai bermain pingpong.
- Ping-Pong? - Yeah.
- Pingpong? - Ya.
Are there any famous Ping-Pong players?
Apa ada pemain pingpong terkenal?
Yeah.
Ya.
Yeah?
Ya?
No. I d-- Let me think.
Tidak. Biar kupikirkan.
I mean, there's gotta be someone famous in Ping-Pong.
Maksudku, pasti ada orang terkenal dalam pingpong.
Right?
Benar?
You look really nice today.
Kau tampak sangat cantik hari ini.
Really?
Sungguh?
I mean, these pants don't really fit.
Maksudku, celana ini tak terlalu pas.
I think they...
Kurasa itu...
I think they make your butt look really nice.
Kurasa itu membuat bokongmu tampak sangat bagus.
Really?
Sungguh?
I think it looks normal.
Kurasa tampak normal.
How would you feel about being a little late to work?
Bagaimana menurutmu bila kau agak terlambat masuk kerja?
I have a team meeting first thing. I'm sorry.
Ada rapat tim pagi ini. Maaf.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Hey.
Hei.
I'll see you, okay?
Sampai nanti, ya?
- Love you. - Love you too.
- Aku mencintaimu. - Aku juga mencintaimu.
Bye.
Sampai jumpa.
Fuck!
Sial!
Oh, fuck.
Sial.
Oh, my God.
Ya ampun.
- Ouch. - Here you go.
- Aduh. - Ini untukmu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
It's the one-year anniversary of the institute today.
ini hari jadi satu tahun institut hari ini.
So, I thought we'd have a party here Saturday.
Jadi, kami pikir akan mengadakan pesta hari Sabtu.
- Happy birthday. - Thank you.
- Selamat ulang tahun. - Terima kasih.
I know it's short notice, but I hope you can be there.
Aku tahu ini pemberitahuan mendadak, tetapi, semoga kau bisa datang.
I usually spend the weekends with Ryan.
Biasanya aku meluangkan akhir pekan bersama Ryan.
Great. Bring him along. I'd love to meet him.
Bagus. Ajak dia. Aku mau bertemu dengannya.
Well, he's actually at a conference this weekend, so--
Sebenarnya dia menghadiri konferensi akhir pekan ini, jadi...
Yeah. And I'm going with him, you know.
Ya. Dan aku akan pergi dengannya.
Trying to be a supportive partner.
Berusaha jadi pasangan yang mendukung.
Well, that's nice.
Itu bagus.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
You're welcome.
Sama-sama.
- I-- Yeah, I better go. - Okay.
- Ya, sebaiknya aku pergi. - Baik.
- I'll see you later. Bye. - Bye.
- Sampai nanti. Salam. - Sampai jumpa.
Sorry.
Maaf.
- Duncan held me up. - It's all right.
- Duncan menundaku. - Tak apa.
At least they seem to be enjoying the singing.
Setidaknya mereka tampak suka menyanyi.
Yeah.
Ya.
Can I ask you something?
Apa aku boleh bertanya?
What?
Apa?
Do you know any famous Ping-Pong players?
Apa kau kenal pemain pingpong terkenal?
Not personally.
Tidak secara pribadi.
No. I mean what about Forrest Gump?
Tidak. Bagaimana dengan Forrest Gump?
- Forrest fucking Gump. - Does that count?
- Forrest Gump sialan. - Itu termasuk?
- Yeah, of course. - Okay.
- Ya, tentu. - Baiklah.
Did Duncan tell you about the reallocation?
Apa Duncan memberi tahu tentang pindah tempat?
No, he just told me about the party.
Tidak, dia hanya memberi tahu soal pesta.
Well, he's had an idea. Thinks that we should specialize more.
Dia punya ide. Berpikir kita harus lebih berspesialisasi.
So he wants each instructor to be an expert on a particular age group.
Jadi, dia ingin tiap instruktur menjadi ahli dalam kelompok usia khusus.
We're gonna be handling couples in their 30s.
Kita akan mengurus pasangan berusia 30-an.
What about Rob and Sally?
Rob dan Sally bagaimana?
- What about them? - Well, we won't work with them anymore?
- Kenapa mereka? - Kita tak akan mengurus mereka lagi?
No.
Tidak.
Fuck.
Sial.
I thought they had a really good chance.
Kukira mereka punya peluang bagus.
I mean, I thought we were doing really good work with them.
Maksudku, kukira kita bekerja dengan baik bersama mereka.
I agree, but Duncan's made up his mind.
Aku setuju, tetapi Duncan sudah memutuskan.
Be too complicated now.
Kini sudah terlalu rumit.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
Feels very sticky.
Rasanya sangat lengket.
Why are we doing this?
Kenapa kita melakukan ini?
I don't know. I thought it'd be fun.
Entahlah. Menurutku mengasyikkan.
No. It's okay. It's just messy. That's all.
Tidak. Tak apa. Hanya berantakan. Itu saja.
I don't like it. I'm sorry.
Aku tak suka. Maaf.
Fuck.
Sial.
It's horrible.
Buruk sekali.
- Should we wait for it to stop? - Yeah.
- Apa kita tunggu hingga berhenti? - Ya.
Are you okay?
Kau tak apa?
Yeah.
Ya.
Excuse me.
Permisi.
I need to tell you something.
Aku harus mengatakan sesuatu.
I...
Aku...
I haven't been very honest with you recently.
Akhir-akhir ini aku tak jujur denganmu.
I didn't take the job at the school.
Aku tak menerima kerja di sekolah.
I've been--
Aku...
I've been working at the Love Training Institute downtown.
Aku bekerja di Institut Pelatihan Cinta di kota.
Why didn't you tell me that?
Kenapa kau tak mengatakan itu kepadaku?
I don't know. I didn't wanna worry you.
Entahlah. Aku tak mau kau cemas.
Why would that worry me?
Kenapa itu membuatku cemas?
I don't know. I was stupid.
Entahlah. Aku bodoh.
I thought if I told you, you would think there was something wrong with us.
Kupikir jika kuberi tahu, kau mengira ada masalah dengan kita.
I don't know-- It was stupid.
Entahlah... Itu bodoh.
Okay.
Baik.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you. I should've.
Maaf aku tak memberi tahu. Seharusnya kuberi tahu.
Don't you wanna say anything?
Kau tak mau mengatakan apa-apa?
I'm gonna take a shower.
Aku akan mandi.
Do you wanna go first?
Kau mau mandi dahulu?
No. I'm gonna watch some TV.
Tidak. Aku akan menonton TV.
Okay.
Baiklah.
- Hey.
- Hei.
- Come in? - Yeah.
- Boleh masuk? - Ya.
Did you lie to me because that training program is nonsense?
Apa kau membohongiku karena program pelatihan itu omong kosong?
Yes.
Ya.
Yeah?
Ya?
Well, I thought if I told you,
Kukira jika aku memberi tahu,
you would encourage me to take the job at school instead.
kau akan mendukungku untuk menerima kerja di sekolah saja.
I wouldn't do that.
Aku tak akan begitu.
I know. I just really wanted to work there.
Aku tahu. Aku cuma ingin bekerja di sana.
I understand that, but it still is--
Aku paham itu, tetapi tetap saja...
- Anna, that's fucking serious. - I know.
- Anna, ini sangat serius. - Aku tahu.
Have you ever hidden anything from me?
Apa kau merahasiakan sesuatu dariku?
Nina Simone bores me to death,
Nina Simone sangat membuatku bosan,
but I listen to her songs because I know you like them.
tetapi kudengarkan lagu-lagunya karena aku tahu kau menyukainya.
Okay.
Baik.
Hey, there's a party at the office on Saturday.
Hei, ada pesta di kantor hari Sabtu.
I told them I couldn't make it,
Kataku aku tak bisa datang,
but if you want to, we could go together.
tetapi jika kau mau, kita bisa datang bersama.
It'll be nice for you to see where I work.
Akan menyenangkan bagimu untuk melihat tempat kerjaku.
- You wanna go in? - Yeah.
- Kau mau masuk? - Ya.
Only you
Hanya kau
Sometimes when I think of her name When it's only a game
Kadang saat kupikirkan namanya Bila hanya permainan
And I need you
Dan aku membutuhkanmu
Listen to the words that I say
Mendengarkan ucapanku
It's getting harder to stay
Makin sulit untuk tetap di sini
When I see you
Bila aku melihatmu
All I needed was the love you gave
Aku hanya perlu cinta darimu
All I needed was another way
Aku hanya perlu cara lain
And all I ever knew Only you
Dan yang kukenal Hanya dirimu
We're ready.
Kami siap.
Okay.
Baiklah.
So, I--
Jadi, aku...
I clamp down and pull?
Aku menjepit ke bawah dan tarik?
Yeah. Just press down hard.
Ya. Tekan saja keras-keras ke bawah.
When you pull, you pull out, not up.
Saat menarik, tarik keluar, bukan ke atas.
Okay. Yeah.
Baik. Ya.
This. Not this.
Ini. Bukan ini.
Exactly.
Benar.
You'll be great. You've got very steady hands.
Kau akan bisa. Tanganmu sangat stabil.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
- We're ready. - Yeah.
- Kita siap. - Ya.
- Okay. Could you grab that?
- Baik. Kau bisa ambil itu?
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
Okay.
Baik.
Okay. So, you know how the test works?
Baik. Jadi, kau tahu cara kerja tes?
- Yes.
- Ya.
So, how you feeling?
Jadi, bagaimana keadaanmu?
I think we're feeling pretty confident
Kurasa kami cukup percaya diri
- after all those exercises. - Great.
- setelah semua latihan itu. - Bagus.
We have been having sex every night this week
Kami bercinta tiap malam pekan ini
for at least an hour each time.
untuk setidaknya satu jam tiap kali.
Lucky you. Well, this will be quicker than that.
Kalian mujur. Ini akan lebih cepat dari itu.
Shall we?
Kita mulai?
Here you go.
Ini dia.
They usually don't scream if you wanna-- No.
Biasanya mereka tak berteriak jika kau mau... Tidak.
- Okay. You're gonna bite down. - You ready?
- Baik. Kau gigit ini. - Kalian siap?
- Great. Okay, just bite down on that. - Thank you.
- Bagus. Baik, gigit saja itu. - Terima kasih.
Have you chosen which nail?
Kau sudah pilih kuku yang mana?
- Yeah. - That's a good nail.
- Ya. - Kuku itu bagus.
Ready?
Siap?
Okay. Three, two, one.
Baik. Tiga, dua, satu.
It'll pass.
Akan pulih.
- Happens every day. Okay? - You're doing great.
- Terjadi tiap hari. Ya? - Kalian berani sekali.
You're doing great.
Kalian berani sekali.
Okay. Let me have a look at that.
Baik. Biar kulihat itu.
- That looks fine. - Keep your fingers straight.
- Itu tampak baik. - Tetap luruskan jari.
You're doing good.
Itu bagus.
Do you want some?
Kau mau?
Thanks. I can't.
Terima kasih. Aku tak bisa.
I'm gluten intolerant. Yeah.
Aku intoleran gluten. Ya.
So, if I have any, I'll die in pain.
Jadi, jika ada, aku akan mati kesakitan.
- Oh, my gosh. Sorry. - It's okay.
- Ya ampun. Maaf. - Tak apa.
It means it's-- I have to eat more healthily, and--
Berarti aku harus makan dengan lebih sehat, dan...
I mean, I miss the taste of some things, but it's fine.
Maksudku, aku melewatkan rasa beberapa hal, tetapi tak apa.
Yeah.
Ya.
You're just gonna have to get used to it.
Kau hanya harus terbiasa dengannya.
To what?
Dengan apa?
To all the zero percents.
Dengan semua nol persen.
Did you think they would get a positive result?
Kau pikir mereka akan mendapat hasil positif?
No. No, not at all, really.
Tidak. Tidak sama sekali.
You know, but even when you know they're not going to get there,
Tetapi bahkan bila kita tahu mereka tak akan dapat hasil positif,
at least they're trying.
setidaknya mereka mencoba.
And it gets worse than that.
Dan makin buruk setelah itu.
The worst is when you think they're perfect for each other and still...
Hal terburuk yaitu ketika kita mengira mereka saling sempurna dan tetap saja...
Look, I know you're sad because we've lost Rob and Sally too,
Begini, aku tahu kau sedih karena kita pun kehilangan Rob dan Sally,
but I promise you, next time, we'll nail it.
tetapi aku berjanji, lain kali, kita akan berhasil.
This is my girlfriend, Gina.
Ini pacarku, Gina.
- Hi. Ryan. Very nice to meet you. - Hi. Anna.
- Hai, Ryan. Senang berkenalan. - Hai, Anna.
- Thank you so much for coming tonight. - Of course.
- Terima kasih mau datang malam ini. - Tentu.
- It's a pretty exciting evening. One year. - You look amazing.
- Malam ini menyenangkan. Satu tahun. - Kau tampak cantik.
I know, right?
Aku tahu, ya?
Now, I understand you're in sales?
Katanya kau dalam bidang penjualan?
- Hey, everyone. Hey. This is Natasha. - Hi.
- Hei. Ini Natasha. - Hai.
Hi, it's so nice to meet you. I've heard a lot about you.
Hai, senang berkenalan. Aku sering mendengar tentangmu.
- Hi. Hey. Ryan. Very nice to meet you. - Hi.
- Hai. Hei. Ryan. Senang berkenalan. - Hai.
- I'm with Anna. Yeah. - Hi, there. Duncan. Nice to meet you.
- Aku bersama Anna. Ya. - Hai, Duncan. Senang berkenalan.
- Hey. - Hey. Ryan.
- Hei. - Hei, Ryan.
- Sorry.
- Maaf.
- Hey. Nice to meet you. Ryan. - Ryan?
- Hei. Senang berkenalan. Ryan. - Ryan?
- Yeah. - Nice to meet you.
- Ya. - Senang berkenalan.
I've heard a lot about you.
Aku sering mendengar tentangmu.
- Yeah? - From Anna. Yeah.
- Ya? - Dari Anna. Ya.
We've been working together, haven't we?
Kami bekerja sama, bukan?
- Last few weeks. - We have.
- Beberapa pekan terakhir. - Benar.
Sorry, your name was...
Maaf, namamu...
- Amir. - Amir. Right.
- Amir. - Amir. Benar.
No, I've heard about you too. Yeah.
Tidak, aku juga mendengar tentangmu. Ya.
- Cool. - Nice.
- Keren. - Bagus.
- Oh, yeah, he is. - Yeah.
- Oh ya, benar. - Ya.
It's been very exciting having him on the team, so...
Sangat menyenangkan dia ada di tim, jadi...
Congratulations. I just wanted to say.
Selamat. Aku cuma mau katakan itu.
- Yeah, I mean... - Thank you.
- Ya, maksudku... - Terima kasih.
Hey, I spoke to Duncan, and we can keep Sally and Rob.
Hei, aku bicara dengan Duncan, dan kita bisa tetap bersama Sally dan Rob.
- What? - Yeah.
- Apa? - Ya.
That's amazing.
Itu hebat.
- Yes. - Thought you'd like it.
- Kupikir kau akan suka.
- Hi. Hey. - Hi.
- Hai. Hei. - Hai.
Are you enjoying the party?
Apa kau menikmati pestanya?
Yeah, everyone's so nice.
Ya, semua orang baik sekali.
Well, you and Amir are such great dancers.
Kau dan Amir penari yang hebat.
Well, we have fun.
Kami bersenang-senang.
- Can I get you a slice? - Yes, please.
- Mau kupotongkan? - Ya, tolong.
And one for Amir too, if you don't mind. Thank you.
Dan satu untuk Amir juga, jika kau tak keberatan. Terima kasih.
I think it might have gluten.
Kurasa mungkin ada glutennya.
Why is that a problem?
Kenapa itu jadi masalah?
Well, I mean, Amir will die from pain if he eats gluten.
Maksudku, Amir akan mati kesakitan jika dia makan gluten.
His allergy?
Alerginya?
Right. That's right.
Benar.
He is gluten-free. I just-- I forgot. So...
Dia tak makan gluten. Aku lupa. Jadi...
- Don't tell him I forgot. - No.
- Jangan beri tahu dia aku lupa. - Tidak.
- So just-- I'll take the one. Thank you. - The one?
- Jadi... Aku ambil yang satu. Terima kasih. - Satu?
Great. Great. Thank you.
Bagus. Terima kasih.
See you out there.
Sampai jumpa di luar.
- Hey. - Hi.
- Hei. - Hai.
I'm just gonna go grab some beers. We're all out.
Aku akan ambil bir. Kami kehabisan.
You leaving?
Kau akan pergi?
Yeah.
Ya.
Ryan, he forgot his scarf. He's just gone inside.
Ryan lupa syalnya. Dia baru masuk.
All right. I'll wait with you.
Baik. Aku akan menunggu denganmu.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- Ya? - Ya.
Where's Natasha?
Di mana Natasha?
She's gone home. Yeah. Early start.
Dia sudah pulang. Ya. Bekerja pagi.
What?
Apa?
Sorry.
Maaf.
Sorry, I was just-- I was thinking.
Maaf, aku cuma... Aku berpikir.
Yeah.
Ya.
What's the purpose of the underwater exercise?
Apa tujuan latihan di bawah air?
You know, with the staring?
Dengan tatap matanya?
I knew it. You never looked at the materials.
Sudah kukira. Kau tak pernah melihat materinya.
I could tell.
Aku bisa tahu.
- Just making it all up as you went along. - Yes, I did.
- Hanya mengarang saat melakukannya. - Ya, benar.
It's supposed to simulate the feeling of breathlessness.
Seharusnya merangsang perasaan tanpa napas.
And the action of staring into each other's eyes.
Dan tindakan menatap satu sama lain.
It can create-- I don't know-- intimacy.
Itu bisa menciptakan, entahlah, keintiman.
It's a nice idea. They all are.
Idenya bagus. Semua bagus.
I mean, once you're reminded of it
Maksudku, setelah kita diingatkan,
you realize how little any of us look each other in the eyes anymore.
kita menyadari ternyata kita jarang saling menatap mata satu sama lain.
Yeah.
Ya.
We're so fucking stupid.
Kita sangat bodoh.
- Well, not you. Well, not just you. - Yeah, I know what you mean.
- Bukan kau. Bukan cuma kau. - Ya, aku paham maksudmu.
And I am fucking stupid.
Dan aku sangat bodoh.
- Hey. - Hi.
- Hei. - Hai.
- Got it. - Great.
- Aku dapat. - Bagus.
- You set? Okay. Good. - Yeah.
- Kau siap? Baik. Bagus. - Ya.
Hey, man, so nice meeting you.
Hei, senang berkenalan.
Have a good night.
Selamat malam.
- See ya. - Night.
- Sampai jumpa. - Malam.
What time did the party finish on Saturday?
Pukul berapa pestanya selesai hari Sabtu?
Next.
Berikutnya.
About 5:00 a.m.
Sekitar pukul 05.00.
I liked your dancing.
Aku suka tarianmu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
How are you two doing?
Apa kabar kalian?
I'm excited! I've never done this before!
Aku senang! Aku belum pernah melakukan ini!
I'm a bit scared, but we'll do it together.
Aku agak takut, tetapi kami akan melakukannya bersama.
Yeah!
Ya!
All right, it's our turn now.
Baik, kini giliran kita.
- Yeah, we can do this. Okay? - No. I--
- Ya, kita bisa ini. Ya? - Tidak. Aku...
- I can't-- No, I can't do this. - We got this.
- Tidak, aku tak bisa ini. - Kita bisa.
- We can do this. - I can't-- I can't fucking do this.
- Kita bisa ini. - Aku tak bisa melakukan ini.
Is everything okay?
Semua baik-baik saja?
We were just wondering if this exercise is really necessary.
Kami ingin tahu apa latihan ini sungguh perlu.
Well, we have found that the adrenaline,
Kami mendapati bahwa adrenalin,
you know, and having your lives in each other's hands, it's pretty effective.
dan mengandalkan jiwa kalian pada satu sama lain, cukup efektif.
It's just that my partner, Andrew,
Hanya saja pasanganku, Andrew,
he just told me that he has a deathly fear of heights.
dia berkata dia sangat takut akan ketinggian.
It's, like, deathly.
Sungguh takut mati.
What if we go with, like, an instructor or someone?
Bagaimana jika kami pergi dengan instruktur atau seseorang?
What if one of you falls in love with the instructor?
Bagaimana jika salah satu dari kalian jatuh cinta dengan instruktur?
You don't have to do this if you don't want to, okay?
Kalian tak harus melakukan ini jika tak mau, ya?
Just have a seat. We'll work it out for later.
Duduk saja. Kita cari solusinya nanti.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Next.
Berikutnya.
- You good? All right. - I'm good.
- Kau tak apa? Baik. - Aku tak apa.
Don't forget to pull the cord, okay?
Jangan lupa tarik talinya, ya?
- Okay. - Yeah.
- Baik. - Ya.
Wunderbar.
Wunderbar.
Look out. Watch out.
Awas. Hati-hati.
- We'll be right there! - Hello?
- Kami segera tiba! - Halo?
We're here. Over here.
Kami di sini. Di sini.
You think this red light's gonna last forever?
Kau pikir lampu merah ini akan menyala selamanya?
Do you have a change of clothes at the office?
Apa kau ada baju ganti di kantor?
Yeah, I'm wearing it.
Ya, aku memakainya.
Well, do you wanna go by your place and pick up some? I don't mind.
Apa kau mau pulang dan mengambil baju? Aku tak keberatan.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, I'll be quick.
Ya, baik. Ya, aku akan cepat.
All right. I'll be quick.
Baiklah. Aku akan cepat.
Do you mind if I come up?
Kau keberatan jika aku naik?
I'll be two minutes.
Akan cepat saja.
Oh, yeah. Just to wash the mud off my hands.
Ya. Cuma mencuci lumpur dari tanganku.
- Right. - Unless I'll bother Natasha.
- Benar. - Kecuali aku mengganggu Natasha.
Oh, no. Nat--
Tidak. Nat...
Natasha's at work. It's just messy.
Natasha sedang bekerja. Rumahku berantakan.
I haven't had a chance to-- You know. It's gross.
Aku tak sempat... Begitulah. Jorok.
Oh, yeah. Okay. No, I'll stay here.
Ya. Baik. Tidak, aku di sini saja.
You know what? Come up.
Ayo naiklah.
Yeah?
Ya?
Yeah, I'll make you a coffee.
Ya. Akan kubuatkan kopi.
- Okay. - Yeah. Okay.
- Baik. - Ya. Baik.
Hey.
Hei.
You can sit here.
Kau bisa duduk di sini.
Yeah.
Ya.
And this is for you.
Dan ini untukmu.
Yeah. And...
Ya. Dan...
if you get bored,
jika kau bosan,
then this is...
maka ini...
interesting.
menarik.
Okay. Yeah. Quick read.
Baik. Ya. Bacaan singkat.
Yeah.
Ya.
I'll be quick.
Aku akan cepat.
Anna.
Anna.
Yeah?
Ya?
Nothing.
Tak apa.
- I'll just be ready in a minute. - Okay.
- Aku akan siap sebentar lagi. - Baik.
- Anna. - You okay?
- Anna. - Kau tak apa?
I don't wanna lose him.
Aku tak mau kehilangannya.
Don't worry, Sally.
Jangan cemas, Sally.
But what if it's-- I mean, what do we do then?
Tetapi bagaimana jika begitu... Maka, apa tindakan kami?
Hey, it's gonna be fine. Okay?
Hei, akan baik-baik saja. Ya?
Why don't you sit down?
Duduklah, ya?
Here, take a seat.
Ini, silakan duduk.
I don't think I like this.
Kurasa aku tak suka ini.
That's okay. Don't worry.
Tak apa. Jangan cemas.
No, I really don't like this.
Tidak, aku sungguh tak suka ini.
Rob, it's just a brief, little moment of pain, and then it's done. Okay?
Rob, hanya rasa sakit sedikit, lalu selesai. Ya?
I don't wanna do it.
Aku tak mau melakukannya.
Okay. Hey.
Baik. Hei.
Close your eyes.
Tutup matamu.
Open your mouth. Bite down. Okay?
Buka mulutmu. Gigit. Ya?
I'm not doing it.
Aku tak mau melakukannya.
Rob. Rob, look at me.
Rob, lihat aku.
It's gonna be okay. We've waited a long time to do this.
Akan baik-baik saja. Kita sudah menunggu lama untuk ini.
I'm sorry, Sally. I'm just fucking freaking out.
Maaf, Sally. Aku hanya ketakutan.
You know how I feel about blood.
Kau tahu aku tak suka darah.
There's really not a lot of blood.
Tak ada banyak darah.
Look, I'm scared too. But it'll be quick. Right?
Begini, aku juga takut. Tetapi akan cepat. Ya?
- Yeah. - I'm sorry.
- Ya. - Maafkan aku.
Look, you guys have been so nice to us,
Kalian sangat baik kepada kami,
- but I'm not in the right place for this. - Rob, look at me.
- tetapi aku tak merasa nyaman. - Rob, lihat aku.
Look at me. Listen, I know you're afraid.
Lihat aku. Begini, aku tahu kau takut.
And more than that, I know you feel vulnerable.
Dan lebih dari itu, aku tahu kau merasa rentan.
I know exactly how that feels.
Aku paham sekali perasaan itu.
I've done this before.
Aku pernah melakukan ini.
It's not as bad as you think.
Tak seburuk perkiraanmu.
- Look at it. Look. - I don't care.
- Lihatlah. Lihat. - Aku tak peduli.
You don't have to do it right now. I have to. Not you.
Kau tak harus melakukannya saat ini. Aku harus. Bukan kau.
Rob, look-- Just sit down and do it. I want you to do this.
Rob, begini... Duduklah dan lakukan. Aku ingin kau melakukannya.
Sally, do you realize this is a form of torture?
Sally, apa kau sadar ini bentuk siksaan?
- My God. You really-- - What do you think?
- Astaga. Kau sungguh... - Menurutmu bagaimana?
I just didn't expect him to behave like that.
Aku tak mengira dia bersikap seperti itu.
Why did we do all these exercises? Just sit down.
Kenapa kita melakukan semua latihan ini? Duduk saja.
- Look, I'm-- - Just sit down and do it.
- Begini, aku... - Duduk dan lakukan.
Do you think they're gonna leave?
Kau pikir mereka akan pergi?
Sally, you realize this is a form of punishment?
Sally, kau sadar ini bentuk siksaan?
I'll do it.
Akan kulakukan.
What?
Apa?
- Please, Rob-- - Just-- Come on.
- Kumohon, Rob... - Ayolah.
- Rob, look at me. It's not that bad. - We can go right now. Please.
- Rob, lihat aku. Tak seburuk itu. - Kita bisa lakukan sekarang. Tolong.
I'm gonna show you. Okay?
Akan kutunjukkan. Ya?
If I do it, will you do it?
Jika kulakukan, apa kau mau?
- Are you doing it? - What?
- Kau melakukannya? - Apa?
If I do it, will you do it?
Jika kulakukan, apa kau mau?
Wh-- I mean--
Maksudku...
I don't know. I mean...
Entahlah. Maksudku...
maybe.
mungkin.
Okay. Then I'm gonna do it, and you're gonna see it's not that bad.
Baik. Maka akan kulakukan, dan kau akan lihat tak seburuk itu.
And-- But then it's your turn.
Dan... Tetapi lalu giliranmu.
Okay.
Baik.
- No. Whoa. What are you doing? - Okay. Okay.
- Tidak. Wah. Apa yang kaulakukan? - Baik.
We can just reschedule. This isn't a big deal.
Kita bisa jadwalkan ulang. Ini tak penting.
Oh, my God.
Astaga.
- Oh, my God.
- Astaga.
It's just a little scratch.
Hanya goresan kecil.
- I can do it. - You can do it.
- Aku bisa. - Kau bisa.
- Okay. You're up next. - You're gonna do it, right, Rob?
- Baik. Kini giliranmu. - Kau akan melakukannya, bukan, Rob?
- Look up there. - No, no. It's all right.
- Lihat ke atas. - Tidak. Tak apa.
You think you can do it? You're gonna do it, Rob?
Kau pikir kau bisa? Kau akan melakukannya, Rob?
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Hey, you're gonna be okay. You're gonna be okay.
Hei, kau akan baik-baik saja.
I'll be okay.
Aku akan baik-baik saja.
- You did really well. - Thank you.
- Kau melakukannya dengan baik. - Terima kasih.
- We're almost... Done. - Hey. You did great.
- Kita hampir... Selesai. - Hei. Kau hebat.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Okay. Coming back soon.
Baik. Segera kembali.
Yeah.
Ya.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Can you just take one step to your left?
Apa kalian bisa selangkah ke kiri?
Yeah-- Split the difference.
Ya... Agak ke tengah.
- Yeah, perfect. - Okay.
- Ya, sempurna. - Baik.
Well, congratulations.
Selamat.
- Thank you. - Well done. Of course.
- Terima kasih. - Bagus. Tentu.
- Good job.
- Bagus.
Okay, great. If I could just get you looking here, please.
Baik, hebat. Ayo melihat ke sini.
Perfect. Okay.
Bagus. Baiklah.
We'll do one more. Just gonna make a slight adjustment here.
Kita buat satu lagi. Hanya menyesuaikan sedikit di sini.
Thank you for your patience.
Terima kasih atas kesabaran kalian.
Looks great. Looks great.
Tampak hebat.
Okay, ready?
Baik, siap?
- Hi. - Hey.
- Hai. - Hei.
How was your day?
Bagaimana harimu?
Difficult.
Sulit.
Why? What happened?
Kenapa? Apa yang terjadi?
It was Ronan again.
Soal Ronan lagi.
He came in completely unprepared and--
Dia datang tanpa persiapan dan...
I don't know, he just made me look like an idiot in the presentation.
Entahlah, dia membuatku tampak bodoh saat presentasi.
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
I tripped in the street and sprained my fingers.
Aku terpeleset di jalan dan jariku terkilir.
Did you go to the hospital?
Apa kau pergi ke rumah sakit?
No. It's fine. It's just in case.
Tidak. Tak apa. Hanya untuk berjaga-jaga.
- You sure? - It's fine. Yeah. Are you hungry?
- Kau yakin? - Tak apa. Ya. Kau lapar?
Yeah. Starving.
Ya. Kelaparan.
Do you want some leftovers from yesterday?
Apa kau mau sisa kemarin?
Sure.
Tentu.
You sure you're okay?
Kau yakin tak apa-apa?
Yeah.
Ya.
Hi. Is Duncan busy?
Hai. Apa Duncan sibuk?
- No. Go ahead. - Okay. Great.
- Tidak. Silakan. - Baik. Bagus.
Do you have a moment?
Kau ada waktu?
Of course.
Tentu.
What's the--
Apa,
I was with my son, Milo, yesterday,
Aku bersama putraku, Milo, kemarin,
and we were playing with these.
dan kami bermain dengan ini.
He made them fly through space.
Dia membuatnya terbang di angkasa.
Then he was trying to make them kiss.
Lalu dia mencoba membuatnya berciuman.
I didn't know you had a son.
Aku tak tahu kau punya anak.
I do. He's nine now. A great kid.
Aku punya. Usianya sembilan tahun. Anak pintar.
He's from my previous marriage.
Dia dari perkawinanku sebelumnya.
His mother and I divorced three years ago.
Ibunya dan aku bercerai tiga tahun yang lalu.
We had a negative test.
Tes kami negatif.
And-- Well, that's why we're no longer together.
Dan, Itu sebabnya kami tak bersama lagi.
Anyhow. What can I help you with?
Begitulah. Apa yang bisa kubantu?
I was wondering if it was possible that
Aku ingin tahu apa mungkin,
one person could be in love--
satu orang bisa jatuh cinta...
I mean, have a positive result with two people at the same time?
Maksudku, punya hasil positif dengan dua orang bersamaan?
Yeah. Sadly, it's not possible.
Ya. Sayangnya, itu mustahil.
It'd be like--
Itu akan jadi,
It'd be like a six-months-pregnant woman
Akan jadi seperti wanita hamil enam bulan
suddenly becoming pregnant with another child.
mendadak jadi hamil dengan anak lain.
Biological impossibility.
Mustahil secara biologis.
Yeah. That's what I thought too, yeah.
Ya. Begitulah pemikiranku juga, ya.
So, he's singing about his mother?
Jadi, dia menyanyi tentang ibunya?
No. "La mer" means "the sea." So, he's singing about the sea.
Bukan. "La mer" berarti "laut". Jadi, menyanyi tentang laut.
Which sea?
Laut mana?
Good question.
Pertanyaanmu bagus.
Not any particular sea.
Bukan laut tertentu.
But just more the sea in general.
Tetapi hanya lautan secara umum.
All the seas?
Semua lautan?
You know, it's more like-- more--
Begini, lebih berupa...
more the sea as a kind of idea.
lautan lebih sebagai semacam ide.
You know? And the idea is...
Paham? Dan idenya...
It's love.
Adalah cinta.
Yeah, the sea is love.
Ya, lautan adalah cinta.
And what about the rest of the lyrics?
Bagaimana dengan sisa liriknya?
He's singing about white sheep and white birds
Dia menyanyikan tentang domba putih dan burung putih
and angels and little, rusted houses. It's--
dan malaikat dan rumah kecil yang berkarat. Itu...
- And how is any of that romantic? - It just is. It's--
- Kenapa itu romantis? - Memang begitu. Itu...
There's a feeling that just--
Ada perasaan yang hanya...
The music is very romantic. It almost doesn't matter what he's saying.
Musiknya sangat romantis. Tak penting apa katanya.
Should I sing now?
Apa aku harus menyanyi sekarang?
Please.
Silakan.
- Oh, shit. - Not again.
- Sial. - Terulang lagi.
Okay, wait.
Baik, tunggu.
I think it's--
Kurasa itu...
- Take it. - Can I?
- Pegang setirnya. - Aku boleh?
Thanks for the lift.
Terima kasih tumpangannya.
No worries. Try not to hurt yourself.
Sama-sama. Jangan lukai dirimu.
Yeah, I'll try.
Ya, aku akan coba.
Can I ask you something?
Apa aku boleh bertanya?
Why do you work at the institute?
Kenapa kau bekerja di institut?
- I mean-- - I like pulling out people's fingernails.
- Maksudku... - Aku suka menarik kuku jari orang.
What? I'm trying to open up here.
Apa? Aku berusaha bersikap terbuka.
I just wanted to be there. You know?
Aku cuma ingin ada di sana.
Maybe understand love a little better. Thought I did.
Mungkin lebih memahami cinta. Kukira aku begitu.
But I don-- Lately--
Tetapi aku tak... Akhir-akhir ini...
Especially lately, I'm not so sure.
Khususnya akhir-akhir ini, aku tak yakin.
Yeah.
Ya.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
You're welcome.
Sama-sama.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Sampai besok.
Have you ever wondered
Apa Anda pernah penasaran
what holds the planets in orbit around the sun?
apa yang menahan planet yang mengorbit memutari matahari?
Or what keeps us from floating off into space?
Atau apa yang mencegah kita terapung di angkasa?
The answer is gravity.
Jawabannya adalah gravitasi.
You remember it's Carrie's birthday tomorrow?
Kau ingat besok ulang tahun Carrie?
Yeah. I got her a present yesterday.
Ya. Aku membelikan hadiah untuknya kemarin.
I didn't see it. What did you get?
Aku tak melihatnya. Kau membelikan apa?
Sorry. I forgot to tell you. An album.
Maaf. Aku lupa memberi tahu. Album.
Which one?
Yang mana?
The Best of Nina Simone.
Lagu-lagu terbaik Nina Simone.
I hope you got the gift receipt.
Semoga kau simpan nota hadiahnya.
I think it's kind of cool that they retook the test. Don't you?
Kurasa bagus mereka mengulang tesnya. Bukan?
I was thinking since I work there and get a discount,
Aku berpikir karena aku bekerja di sana dan dapat diskon,
that we could take advantage of it and do it again.
kita bisa memanfaatkan hal itu dan mengulanginya.
Yeah. You know, just for fun.
Ya. Begitulah, untuk iseng.
No way. That's not my idea of fun, having my fingernails ripped out.
Tak mau. Aku tak mau mencabut kuku jariku cuma untuk iseng.
I know, it's just--
Aku tahu, hanya...
You know, the institute has got such a good reputation,
Institut itu punya reputasi bagus,
and with the discount--
dan dengan diskon...
Yeah, we've already passed the test. Why would we take it again?
Ya, kita sudah lulus tesnya. Kenapa harus mengulangnya?
Well, 'cause, like, Carrie and Andy took it.
Karena, Carrie dan Andy melakukannya.
I don't care what other people do.
Aku tak peduli tindakan orang lain.
...that we still don't fully understand.
...yang masih belum kita pahami.
But it's one of the most important forces in the universe.
Tetapi salah satu daya paling penting di alam semesta.
And it's what makes life
Dan itu yang membuat kehidupan
on Earth possible.
mungkin ada di Bumi.
- Without gravity the planet... - Do you think that we should...
- Tanpa gravitasi, planet... - Kau pikir kita harus...
...would fly off into space.
...akan terapung di angkasa.
...do it? To retake the test?
...melakukannya? Mengulang tesnya?
And have your feelings changed?
Apa perasaanmu berubah?
No.
Tidak.
Yeah, 'cause my feelings haven't changed.
Ya, karena perasaanku belum berubah.
You know, if anything, I feel like my feelings have only gotten stronger.
Malah, aku merasa perasaanku makin kuat.
- Yeah, but it's not about that. - What's it about?
- Ya, tetapi bukan soal itu. - Soal apa?
It's--
Itu...
I don't know. It's--
Entahlah. Itu...
I don't wanna have this conversation.
Aku tak mau membicarakan ini.
I'm sorry, what do you want?
Maaf, kau mau apa?
Yeah, I think it's normal to get into a bit of a routine.
Ya, kurasa normal untuk memasuki, sedikit rutinitas.
Right? I think that's the nature of a relationship.
Benar? Kurasa itu inti sebuah hubungan.
You can't take it for granted.
Kita tak bisa meremehkannya.
I think a relationship should be worked on every day. All the time.
Kurasa hubungan harus diupayakan tiap hari. Sepanjang waktu.
Okay.
Baiklah.
And?
Dan?
Nothing. Forget it.
Tak ada. Lupakan saja.
Why aren't you sleeping?
Kenapa kau tak tidur?
Can't sleep.
Tak bisa tidur.
Okay. Let's go and do it now.
Baik. Ayo lakukan sekarang.
What? Now?
Apa? Sekarang?
Yeah.
Ya.
Do you wanna come and see the results together?
Kau mau ikut dan lihat hasilnya bersama?
I don't know how I'm gonna explain this at work.
Aku tak tahu caraku menjelaskan ini di kantor.
It was positive.
Itu positif.
Why do you need to explain it?
Kenapa kau harus menjelaskannya?
We're never doing this again.
Kita tak akan melakukan ini lagi.
Yeah.
Ya.
Morning.
Selamat pagi.
Amir. I--
Amir, aku...
I need to talk to you about something.
Aku harus membicarakan sesuatu.
I--
Aku...
Hi, excuse me. So, Marcus, he's out sick today.
Hai, permisi. Jadi, Marcus sakit hari ini.
But he had two clients that were due for testing right now.
Tetapi dia punya dua klien yang harus dites sekarang.
Would you two mind stepping in? I'm sorry for the late notice.
Apa kalian mau melakukannya? Maaf pemberitahuanku mendadak.
Yeah. Sure.
Ya. Tentu.
Yeah, it's fi-- I don't think we have any tests booked this morning.
Ya, tak apa... Kurasa kami tak ada pemesanan tes pagi ini.
Great. There's his file. Just take a quick look at it.
Bagus. Ini berkasnya. Lihatlah dengan cepat.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
What were you gonna say?
Kau mau mengatakan apa?
Nothing.
Tak ada.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I'll go set up the tests.
Aku akan menyiapkan tesnya.
Amir, would you mind taking a look at something?
Amir, apa kau mau memeriksa sesuatu?
- Sure. - What? Is everything okay?
- Tentu. - Apa? Semua baik-baik saja?
Yeah.
Ya.
I think there's something wrong with the machine.
Kurasa ada masalah dengan mesinnya.
Won't be a minute.
Sebentar saja.
There was a strange sound, and then it just stopped.
Ada suara aneh, lalu berhenti.
Oh, shit.
Sial.
Okay.
Baik.
Okay, what are we gonna tell 'em?
Baik, kita beri tahu apa kepada mereka?
I need to tell you something.
Aku harus mengatakan sesuatu.
What?
Apa?
I tested our fingernails.
Aku mengetes kuku jari kita.
What? Wait, whose fingernails?
Apa? Tunggu, kuku jari siapa?
Ours.
Kita.
What do-- How did--
Apa yang... Bagaimana...
Look, I know you're not with Natasha.
Begini, aku tahu kau tak bersama Natasha.
She doesn't know anything about you.
Dia tak tahu apa-apa tentangmu.
She's my neighbor.
Dia tetanggaku.
What were the results?
Apa hasilnya?
Fifty percent.
Lima puluh persen.
So I...
Jadi aku...
I retested with Ryan last night and it was 100%.
Aku mengetes ulang dengan Ryan semalam dan itu 100%.
Excuse me? Is everything okay in there?
Maaf? Semua baik-baik saja di sana?
I mean, I don't know. I don't know what it means.
Maksudku, aku tak tahu. Aku tak tahu apa artinya.
I mean, maybe that-- I don't know. Maybe that you're in--
Maksudku, mungkin... Entahlah. Mungkin kau...
you're in love with me, and...
kau jatuh cinta kepadaku dan...
I'm not in love with you.
aku tak jatuh cinta kepadamu.
Hello?
Halo?
Yeah, I think it does.
Ya, kurasa begitu.
I just gotta--
Aku hanya harus...
Thanks. Okay.
Terima kasih. Baik.
- Take care. All right. - Thanks.
- Jaga dirimu. Baik. - Terima kasih.
- Okay.
- Baik.
It's a shame they got a negative test result.
Sayang hasil tes mereka negatif.
But I am glad we got the machine fixed quickly.
Tetapi aku senang mesinnya segera diperbaiki.
Make sure to send them vouchers for a free test, all right?
Pastikan untuk mengirim mereka voucher untuk tes gratis, ya?
Where did Amir go?
Amir pergi ke mana?
I have no idea.
Aku tak tahu.
He called me.
Dia meneleponku.
He had to leave urgently. He said he wasn't feeling well.
Dia harus segera pergi. Katanya dia tak merasa sehat.
He might have to miss a few days of work.
Mungkin dia harus cuti sakit beberapa hari.
Maybe it's the same thing that Marcus had.
Mungkin tertular penyakit yang sama dengan Marcus.
I guess we'll get it figured out tomorrow.
Kurasa kita akan tahu besok.
- Hey! Happy birthday! - Thank you.
- Hei! Selamat ulang tahun! - Terima kasih.
I'm gonna go and grab something to eat.
Aku akan cari makanan.
It's past midnight.
Sudah lewat tengah malam.
I know. I didn't eat much at the party.
Aku tahu. Aku tak makan banyak di pesta.
I think we have something in the fridge.
Kurasa ada sesuatu di kulkas.
I feel like chicken soup. Do you want some?
Aku ingin sup ayam. Kau mau?
No. I'm tired.
Tidak. Aku lelah.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Hi.
Hai.
I brought you some soup.
Kubawakan sup untukmu.
You were sick, so I brought you some soup.
Kau sakit, jadi kubawakan sup.
Yeah.
Ya.
Do you want to eat it now?
Kau mau makan sekarang?
- Now, now? - Yeah.
- Sekarang juga? - Ya.
Soup's really bad.
Supnya sangat tidak enak.
I know.
Aku tahu.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
It was the only place that was open.
Hanya tempat itu yang buka.
It's fine. Just don't ask me to eat it.
Tak apa. Jangan minta aku memakannya.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I think I--
Kurasa aku...
I think I wanna kiss you.
Kurasa aku ingin menciummu.
You have a scar just there.
Kau ada bekas luka di sana.
Yeah. Yeah, I had my appendix out.
Ya, aku operasi usus buntu.
Think I was eight.
Kurasa usiaku delapan tahun.
Looks like a tiny train track.
Mirip rel kereta api kecil.
It does.
Memang.
Tickles.
Geli.
What about Ryan?
Ryan bagaimana?
I don't know.
Entahlah.
Sometimes...
Kadang...
I don't know. Sometimes being in love is lonelier than being alone, you know?
Entahlah. Kadang jatuh cinta lebih kesepian daripada sendirian.
So, I've tested many times.
Jadi, aku sering melakukan tes.
I've never been positive till now.
Hingga saat ini aku tak pernah positif.
And-- Yeah. So, I just wanted to know what was wrong with me.
Dan, Ya, jadi ingin tahu apa yang tak beres denganku.
What's wrong with me?
Ada apa denganku?
I don't wanna go back.
Aku tak mau pulang.
As in you wanna stay the night?
Maksudmu kau mau menginap?
Yeah, I wanna stay here.
Ya, aku mau tetap di sini.
I would love that.
Aku mau sekali.
I would really love that.
Aku sungguh mau sekali.
But you saw the test.
Tetapi kau lihat tesnya.
I don't care.
Aku tak peduli.
You tested positive with Ryan. Twice.
Kau dites positif dengan Ryan. Dua kali.
I'm thirsty.
Aku haus.
Maybe it's better if you leave.
Mungkin sebaiknya kau pergi.
Is that what you want?
Itukah keinginanmu?
No.
Tidak.
But what are we gonna do?
Tetapi apa yang akan kita lakukan?
I don't know.
Aku tak tahu.
I'm tired.
Aku lelah.
Okay.
Baik.
Hey.
Hei.
Just stay the night.
Menginaplah malam ini.
I'll take you home in the morning.
Kau akan kuantar pulang besok pagi.
Anna?
Anna?
Anna, What are you doing?
Anna, apa yang kaulakukan?
- Oh, my God. - Hey.
- Astaga. - Hei.
What have you done?
Apa yang kaulakukan?
Why would you do this?
Kenapa kau melakukan ini?
- I don't-- - Look at me. I'm here.
- Aku tak... - Lihat aku. Aku di sini.
- I don't want them anymore. - I'm right here with you.
- Aku tak mau ini lagi. - Aku di sini denganmu.
- Okay. - I'm here with you. Okay?
- Baik. - Aku di sini bersamamu. Ya?
Okay? Okay.
Ya? Baik.
Shouldn't have done this.
Seharusnya kau tak melakukan ini.
I'm here with you, Anna.
Aku di sini bersamamu, Anna.
It's okay.
Tak apa.
This is gonna hurt.
Ini akan menyakitkan.